




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The World-Wide-Web on K-State CC 120 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc120/1-www/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in The World-Wide-Web on K-State CC 120 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 10:53:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc120/1-www/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc120/1-www/01-introduction/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc120/1-www/01-introduction/index.html</guid>
      <description>While working for CERN (the European Organization for Nuclear Research), Tim Burners-Lee proposed bringing the ideas of hyper-text documents together with emerging Internet technologies like the Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) and the Domain Name System (DNS) to create the World-Wide Web. He defined the Hyper Text Transfer Protocol (HTTP), the first web server, and the first web browser, in 1990 demonstrating the feasibility of the idea. Since that time, the web has grown to contain around 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Vision of Sir Tim Berners Lee</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc120/1-www/02-the-technologies-of-the-web/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc120/1-www/02-the-technologies-of-the-web/index.html</guid>
      <description>When Tim-Berners Lee presented his original ideas for the World-Wide Web, it consisted of a protocol for requesting web documents - HTTP, and a markup language those documents could be written in - HTML. These initial technologies continue to be the foundation of the world-wide web, and have been enhanced by additional languages to style webpages - CSS - and modify them - JavaScript.
Each of these technologies has continued to evolve under the guidance of the W3C.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Standards?</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc120/1-www/03-why-standards/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc120/1-www/03-why-standards/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Web Standards the W3C and ECMA International maintain are a critical piece of the web infrastructure. Having a standard for how HTML, CSS, and JavaScript should be interpreted by a web browser means that every browser can display the same webpage in the same way - allowing you the choice of your favorite browser without worrying your web browsing experience would be impacted.
This was not always the case; during the early days of the world-wide-web in a period known as the Browser Wars the browsers Netscape Navigator and Internet Explorer both added features to their browsers not defined in the standards, and web developers had to decide which browser to build against.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc120/1-www/04-summary/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc120/1-www/04-summary/index.html</guid>
      <description>This textbook will guide you through the three core client-side web technologies (HTML, CSS, &amp;amp; JS), as well as discuss the role HTTP plays in retrieving resources for a web client (like a browser) from the web. It is organized into chapters focused on each of those technologies in turn:
The World-Wide-Web Hyper-Text Transfer Protocol Hyper-Text Markup Language Cascading Style Sheets JavaScript Once you understand client-side web technologies, you may want to turn your attention to the server side.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>